New England Hospital for Women and Children Records, 1792-1994
Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College
New England Hospital for Women and Children records
1792 - 1994
New England Hospital for Women and Children
MS 339
27 boxes (9.5 linear ft.)
Sophia Smith Collection Smith College Northampton, MA
Women's hospital. This hospital was, for more than a century, a teaching hospital for women doctors and a place where women could receive treatment from them. It was the first hospital in Boston to offer obstetrics, gynecology, and pediatrics all in one facility. Material includes memoranda, written histories, photographs and scrapbooks. Also documented are such topics as a 1915 controversy over abortion, using chloroform as an anesthetic, and African American interns. The collection includes several hundred letters collected for their autograph value for fund-raising fairs. The letters do not relate to the Hospital; content includes woman suffrage, abolition, freedmen's education, literature, and Civil War relief. Notable correspondents include: Louisa May Alcott, Susan B. Anthony, Alice Stone Blackwell, Elizabeth Blackwell, Lydia Maria Child, Thomas Wentworth Higginson, Julia Ward Howe, Henry Wadsworth Longfellow, Elizabeth Palmer Peabody, Lucy Stone, Harriet Beecher Stowe, and John Greenleaf Whittier.
The New England Hospital for Women and Children (NEH), founded by Dr. Marie Zakrzewska and Ednah Dow Cheney, opened in Boston on July 1, 1862. It was, for more than a century, a teaching hospital where women doctors and nurses could study and practice medicine and women could receive treatment from female doctors. It was the first hospital in Boston to offer obstetrics, gynecology, and pediatrics all in one facility. The concept grew out of Zakrzewska's close friendships with influential women in Boston. These early supporters included reformers such as Abby May, Caroline Severance and philanthropist, Lucy Goddard. Goddard served as president for the first twenty-fuve years until 1887. Cheney served as secretary, becoming president in 1887. She resigned in 1902. During its first ten years the NEH served primarily the immigrant population of the area. Despite the hard financial times during the Civil War, Dr. Zakrzewska and her supporters raised enough money to sustain the hospital in its early years. Throughout the nineteenth century the NEH grew steadily from ten beds and approximately $150 in assets in 1862 to a budget of $146,000 in 1872. Among the doctors who served the NEH were Dr. Susan Dimock and Dr. Lucy Sewall. The country's first trained nurse, Linda Richards, studied at NEH in 1873; and the first African-American nurse, Mary Eliza Mahoney, graduated in 1875. Born and nourished by separatism, the nineteenth century solution to sexual discrimination, the hospital, by the time of its centennial in 1912, was facing conflict over integration and the challenge of justifying its existence as an all-woman's hospital. This was due in part to a growing tendency among women doctors to achieve professional equality with men, manifested by the integration of the medical profession, specialization, membership in male-dominated medical societies, and affiliation at male dominated hospitals. There were continual financial troubles as well and in the 1950s, the United Community Services of Greater Boston recommended that the hospital be open to male physicians. In response to this pressure, the board of directors adopted one of its recommendations and changed the institution's official name from the New England Hospital for Women and Children to the New England Hospital, thus indicating their willingness to accept men as patients. The controversy continued through the 1950s and 1960s. Following a long battle led by Blanche Ames Ames, Chair of the hospital's board of directors, the NEH closed in 1969 and reopened as an outpatient clinic. The clinic was named the Dimock Community Health Center.
See also Hospital With A Heart: Women Doctors and the Paradox of Separatism in the New England Hospital, 1862-1969, by Virginia G. Drachman (Ithaca, New York, Cornell University Press, 1984).
The records of the New England Hospital contain manuscripts, photographs, annual reports, minutes, a scrapbook, printed material, legal and financial records, correspondence and memorabilia. They are divided into two parts. The first (SERIES I-V) is a group of miscellaneous papers dealing with the early history of the hospital. It includes material related to fund drives and anniversary celebrations (1896-1962); manuscript and published Annual Reports, 1863-1955; correspondence (1847-1922); business and financial papers (1859-1920); circulars and rules; memoranda and minutes of physicians' meetings (1876-1917) (including one bound volume of minutes); photographs, a scrapbook; and miscellaneous subjects including a controversy over abortion (1915), the use of chloroform as an anesthetic (1888), and African-American women interns. There is also application material from women medical students seeking internships, including letters, forms, recommendations, and transcripts (1891-1926). The second part (SERIES VI) contains several hundred letters collected for their autograph value for sale at nineteenth century fund-raising fairs. These letters are largely from the correspondence of Ednah Dow Cheney and Eva Channing. While they do not relate in content to the Hospital, they are authored by major literary, political, and religious figures of the latter half of the nineteenth century. They form a valuable collection of source material in the social and intellectual history of the period. Topics include woman suffrage, social services, abolition, freedmen's education, literature, and Civil War relief. The correspondents cover a wide range of notables, including: Louisa May Alcott (1882-88), Alice Stone Blackwell (1886-1903); Elizabeth Blackwell (1848-87); George Washington Cable (1877-1904), Lydia Maria Child (1860-69), Thomas Wentworth Higginson (1857-1902); Julia Ward Howe (1862-1900); Henry Wadsworth Longfelllow (1864-78), Elizabeth Palmer Peabody (1881-87), Lucy Stone (1879-93), Harriet Beecher Stowe (1860-70), and John Greenleaf Whittier (1862-90). For additional noted correspondents see Search Terms.
These records provide a unique insight into medical education and health care for women in the late nineteenth and early twentieth centuries, the sometimes difficult and contentious internal challenges within the Hospital, and its struggle to maintain its independence in a rapidly changing social and cultural environment.
The bulk of the hospital records are dated between 1862 and 1956. They are divided into six series: I. History, II. Personal, III. Financial, IV. Correspondence, V. Subjects, VI. Autograph Collection
This collection is organized into six series:
I. History
II. Personal
III. Financial
IV. Correspondence
V. Subjects
VI. Autograph Collection
Appendix: List of Interns
1891 Margaret Moore
1892 Mary Augusta Camp Jannat Ernestine Hills Maria Ingram Henrietta P. Johnson Harriet McCalmont Mary Howell Miller Fanne A. Merriam Martha E. Pike Miriam T. Runyon Rose Slobodinsky H. Adeline Thompson
1893 Clarissa Bigelow Mary Jones Brewster Virginia Buttermore Mary E. Caminade Eva Carroll Mary A. Charteris Eleanor Chestnut Florence DeHart Sarah E. Evans Louise H. Greene Alice Hamilton Louise H. Hart Katherine S. Munhall Mary A. Platter Delia M. Rice Mary Sanderson Eleanor Tomes Frances J. Trout Della Mary Walker Emma P. Weeks Georgiana Whiting
1894 Mary E. Bassett Elizabeth Bulkley Mary E. Christy Jenny G. Dreuman Emma H. Hodge Mary Salona Holmes Louise A. Husted Harriet L. Knox Susan Hunt Lawrence Mary A. Leonard Abby Noyes Little Mary Williamina Lougee Elizabeth McLuaghry Henrietta Mood Lois Neville Marietta Newcombe Phoebe R. Norris Helen Nuzume Maybelle M. Park Eleanor Parry Julia Riddle Mary D. Rushmore Emma Scott Sidonia Weiss Grace E. White
1895 Sarah Campbell Allan Edith V. Anderson Elizabeth Beharrell Marie Chard Jane Downes Kelly Alice Littell
1899 Martha E. Lowell
1900 Henrietta M. Farquharson Julia Grice Mabel L. Haninton Mary W. Marvell Hannah G. Myrick Harriet D.W. Showers Mary Frances Sweet Maud Emily Taft
1901 Jean Isabel Best Helen N. Binford Sarah Allen Castle Annie L. Conner Susan Rogers Corson Eliza Dadmun Florence West Duckering Caroline S. Finley Gertrude Felker Lenore Hamilton Gageby Maude Glasgow Ella A. Hackett Helen Robertson Howe Louise H. Keator Isabella Cloe Little Bella Lysaught Elizabeth Moore Ellen O'Flaherty Susanna Otis Margaret Parks Eleanor Preston Alice H. Purvis Belle A. Schisler Martha Smith Jane Beck Smith Charlotte Steckel Carolotta M. Swett Stella M. Turner
1902 Rose Mary Blakelidge Blanche M. Dennes Adele Russell Emerson Rebecca M. Evans Phoebe Ferris Mary E. Gill Florence Gilman Minerva Goodman Cora E. Harriman Eleanor J. Hill Ruth Peabody Hume Marion H. Hunsicker Elizabeth Jaeger Mabel V. Kennard Elizabeth McMaster Martha Marlatt Velma E. Powell M. Catherine Schroeder Cynthia Steers Alice Weld Tallant Susan B. Tallman Isabelle M. Thomson Jeannette C. Welch Jessie Wheeler Anna Bowden White Isabelle Smith Wood
1903 Mary Brooks Baird Annie R. Baker Blanche C. Boyle Marjorie Burnham Mary S. Crosswell Genevieve Gustin Sophie G. Laws Josephine A. Line Eleanor F. Lucas Esther Mitchell Mary E. Morse Margaret L. Noyes Sarah Gardner Genevieve Pierson Olive W. Rae Catherine H. Travis Stella L. Wilkinson Julia R. Youngman
1904 Helen P. Beattie Maria Washburn Bliss Helen Elizabeth Brooks Rebecca Clark Sarah E. Finch Julia Hardin Gertrude M. Hastings Sue L. Koons Katherine H. Law Elsie P. Miller Stella L. Mullin Elsie Seelye Pratt Victoria Reid Mary L. Rosenteil F. Matina Tanquary Edna M. Thomas Louisa C. Zimmerman
1905 Elizabeth Bagshaw Nellie Baker Alice May Ballou Alice H. Bigelow May B. Calloghan Zella M. Clark Marguerite S. Crockett Rose Cohen
1905 Edith M. Conser Harriet Davies M. Ellen Douglas Mary Robins Findlater Agavine Gilbakian Sarah Mabel Grier Miriam E. Griffin Edith Hale Jessie Hattendarf Harriet A. Hook Edith C. Kline Li Bi Cu L. Mae Lichtenwalner Edith Loeber Agnes Mikkelsen Abbie M. O'Keefe Katherine P. Raymond Hanna E. Reid Katharine B. Scott Maude S. Slocumb Alice W. Smith Myrtle Smith Alice Steffian Maude W. Taylor Frances P. Waugh
1906 Vivia B. Appleton Alice Baxter Inez A. Bentley Phoebe M. Bogart Anna M. Cooke Norma B. Elles Miriam Gardner Helen W. Ham Josephine D. Hunt Henriette Johnson Laura M. Johnson Bessie B. Little Melissa Manderson Mary T. Martin Louise Morrow Agnes G. Murdoch Elizabeth Y. Myres Maud A. Powell
1906 Katherine Stull Editha E.Taylor Lily Ethel Taylor Anna Weld Hagar Wishart Miriam Yampolsky
1907 Elizabeth B. Ball Elizabeth E. Bowen Florence A. Bullen Margaret C. Calder M. Blanche Campbell Gladys L. Carr Martha Crofut Susan W. Field H. Amanda Johnson Marion Eleanor Leeper Saidie B. Lindberg Florence L. McKay Maud L. Menten Ida B. Orecchia Grace Peele Mehitable C. Proctor Lucy A. Reed Clara Seippel Pearl J. Sproule Geneva Tryon
1908 Letitia D. Adams Lily F. Boyington Gladys Cooper Desire M. Dunn Lulu Lee Angeline M. Lemon Marion C. Littlefield Frances R. Ritchie Ellen M. Rowe Sara L. Smalley Elizabeth Sohon Emily S. Stark Bessie L. Sweet Ada H. Tedford Anna J. Waite Annie Wood Eulalie Wood
1909 Elizabeth M. Abbe Marion E. Blackman Nellie M. Cole Alice M. Flood Ellen M. Johnosn Florence A. King Cora I. Kipp Ida R. Lantz Rosamond Leacock Sadie A. Mulvanity Anna I. Murphy Emily M. Oberlin Marie Seixas Mary Shutan Jennie Smillie Estelle Smith Edith R. Spaulding Sara E. Swezey Mary M. Wheeler Evelyn Windsor
1910 Mary E. Brogan Isabel Bogan Ethel L. Boren Olga Bridgman, Mary P. Brooke Caroline S. Brown Elizabeth Bruyn Mary E. Burns Electa W. Carrier Elizabeth D. Carroll Edna V. Dale Anna K. Davenport Grace DeWitt Jessie A. Dow Mary B. Fimpel Edna W. Guest Myrtle Jack Margaret A. Judge Ruth M. Lance Christina M. Leonard Jessie McDonald Helen O'S. McGarry Esther K. Payne
1910 Bessie T. Pullan Jettie J. Resnick Mary I. Roberts Eleanor Slater Lucia Willard
1911 Louise Auerbach Leontine E. Bacon Jean Christie M. Blanche Cooney Sarah E. Coppinger Ruth J. Crasson Rose Donk Susie L. Fotheringham Emilie C. Gorrell Audrey Goss Mary A. Hopkins Nancy B. Jenison Gertrude Johnson Marion M. Kershaw Bella Levinson Portia McKnight Jessie Robertson Susan A. Rutkus Frances Shostac Leota Spurgeon Elizabeth Stewart Goldie E. Zimmerman
1912 Jane Bigelow Florence Chadwick Mary C. Couch Annie R. Elliot Kate H. Elting Maude L. Etheridge Lucie G. Forrer Hattie Greenblatt Ethel Hayes Irma Howard Anna Hubert Edith A. McDowell Cordelia I. MacNaughton Bernadette M. McWeeney Geraldine Oakley Olive Pippy Alma Read
1912 Margaretta R. Rieger Theresa C. Snyder Vernie E. Woodward
1913 Emma M. Ackerman Hazel Bonness Ellen C. Cover Helen G. Craige Erminie S. Cryder Georgia A. Filley Margaret V. Grogan Marie B. Kast Marian Kenworthy Ray B. LaCroix Eveline Lyle Bernadette McWeen Mary T.V. Moore Beatrice Alma Reed Bonnell M. Souder Olga Stastny Marie C. Strom
1914 Blanche L. Atwood Kate B. Bogle Myrtle M. Brill Irene Chandler Clara G. Cook Lora G. Dyer Evelyn P. Hyatt Ruth Ingraham Jennie McIntosh Minnie L. Maffett Ina L. Moore Katharine A. Nye Clara A. Sargent Clara Shellmanner Mildred C. Williams
1915 Frances P. Cepelka Lucy McM. Elliott Clara Gottschalk Mary Hanka Faith F. Hardy Evelyn H. Hunt
1915 Grace A. Joslin Elizabeth Kilpatrick Mollie King Hie-ding Lin Clara C. Leach Eliza A. Melkonia Mary F. Mernin Mary T. Muldoon Agnes Muldoon Kathalyn Voorhis Ruth A. Warner
1916 Hannah J. Beatty Jane R. Breese Lona Bulyea Anna Q. Churchill Margaret W. Farwell Henrietta S. Frederichson Martha Gifford Ethel R. Kathleen Harrington Sarah R. Kelman Ruth M. McGuire Helen A. Moore Bessie N. Newcomb Elizabeth V. O'Neill Mildred J. Roberts Bertha M Schafer Fanny E. Shutts Lillian R. Smith Grace Spencer
1917 Hildegarde C. German Virgil Martha Gilchrist Anna L. Hooper Alice C. Scully Anna P. Walsh
1918 Frederica Cliff
1920 Annie B. Chung Anna B. Grey Ethel A. Gwin Ruth V. Hemenway Edith Kerkhoff Ruth Leonard Ruth Patrick Mary G. Schroeder Margery M. Stauffer
1921 Margaret Bell Lillina Bendeke-Parson Eleanore Glebow Dorothy Grey Mary E. Hanko Margaret Howard 1921Josephine L. Kaye Ruth L. King Ruth M. Mahon Adeline Muelchi Margaret W. Pirsch Florence M. Ross Helen W. Spencer Rita B. Tower Marjorie Woodman
1922 Rena M. Bigalow Zilpha Galloway Elizabeth L. Broyles Tsing Liea Li Christine MacLeod Gertrude C. Nicolson Ethel B. Perry Jennie B. Rozell
1923 Ruth Sin-Ging Ho Hanna C. Johnson Mary F. Knott Georgia Krusich Caroline McMath Sarah Margaret Peyton Grace M. Santoro Anne Tarshis
1924 Mildred J. Buzza Louise de Schweinitz Ruth E. Hull Frances M. Johnson Mildred N. Johnson Lillian Kositza Margaret M. Loder Charlotte McCarthy Austis P. Manton Laura H. Muir Isabel B. Turner Helen M. Weistling
1925 Lillian deArmit Jennie D. Hippolitus Esther Mathers Fatima V. Reshid Margaret Robertson Esther Somerfield Esther Tuttle Wilma Weeks
1926 Miriam A. Albertson Felicia A. Banes Veronica C. Barrett Isabella F. Borden Ethel T. Calhoun Eleanor E. Cowan Susannah Friedman Rachel Goldberg Faith L. Meserve Rose C. Munro Edith E. Pasmore Hilla Sheriff Margaret A. Telfer Helen B. Tursky Anna M. Young
Information on Use
Terms of Access and Use
The records are open to research according to the regulations of the Sophia Smith Collection.
Additional Formats
The finance committee records (1877-1915), the records of the physicians meetings (1876-1917), and A Practical Illustration of "Woman's Right To Labor;" or, A letter from Marie E. Zakrzewska, M.D., edited by Caroline Dall are available on the History of Women microfilm series (New Haven: Research Publications) available in the Sophia Smith Collection and Neilson Library, Smith College and through interlibrary loan.
History of the Collection
The Records of the New England Hospital for Women and Children were given to the Sophia Smith Collection between 1962 and 1964 by the Board of Directors through the efforts of Mary Byers Smith (Smith '08), member of the board. Copies of photographs of Bessie H. Simpson were donated in 2009 by Janet McIiver.
Search Terms
Alcott, Louisa May, 1832-1888; Anthony, Susan B. (Susan Brownell), 1820-1906; Blackwell, Alice Stone, 1857-1950; Blackwell, Elizabeth, 1821-1910; Cheney, Ednah Dow Littlehale, 1824-1904; Channing, Eva; Child, Lydia Maria Francis, 1802-1880; Diaz, Abby Morton, 1821-1904; Dimock, Susan J., 1847-1875; Hale, Edward Everett, 1822-1909; Higginson, Thomas Wentworth, 1923-1911; Howe, Julia Ward, 1819-1910; Jacobs, Harriet A (Harriet Ann), 1813-1897; Jewett, Sarah Orne, 1849-1909; Longfellow, Henry Wadsworth, 1807-1882; Mahoney, Mary Eliza; Peabody, Elizabeth Palmer, 1804-1894; Richards, Linda, 1841-1930; Sewell, Lucy; Stone, Lucy, 1818-1893; Stowe, Harriet Beecher, 1811-1896; Sumner, Charles, 1811-1874; Thomas, M. Carey (Martha Carey), 1857-1935; Washington, Booker T., 1856-1915; Zakrzewska, Marie E., (Marie Elizabeth), 1829-1902; New England Hospital for Women and Children--History--Sources; Authors, American--Correspondence; Autographs--Collections; Gynecology--United States--History--Sources; Hospitals, gynecological and obstetric--History--Sources; Hospitals--New England--History--Sources; Medicine--Study and teaching--United States--History--Sources; Nursing--Study and teaching--United States--History--Sources; Obstetrics--United States--History--Sources; Physicians--United States--History--Sources; Sex discrimination in medical education--United States--History--Sources; Social reformers--United States; Women in medicine--United States--History--Sources; Women physicians--United States--History; Women's health services--United States--History--Sources
Additional Information
Related Material
There are letters and application material regarding internships for Ruth V. Hemenway, Louise deSchweinitz and Alice B. Tallant whose papers are also in the Sophia Smith Collection. Related material can also be found in the Ames Family Papers (under Blanche Ames Ames). The Francis A. Countway Library of Medicine at Harvard University has patient records, 1862-1902 and some administrative records. The Schlesinger Library also at Harvard University has administrative records, 1914-1954. There is additional material as well in the Ames Family Papers in the Sophia Smith Collection.
Additional records of the hospital can be found in at the Francis A. Countway Library of Medicine at Harvard University.
See also the National Library of Medicine's exhibit Changing the Face of Medicine for pages on Mary Putnam Jacobi and Marie E. Zakrzewska.
- SERIES I. HISTORY 1859-1994, 2.25 linear ft.
  This series contains general history of the New England Hospital from its founding in 1862 through the United Way controversy of the early 1950s to its final closing in 1969. It includes, memoranda and correspondence, information about its anniversaries and fund-raising fairs, an incomplete run of annual reports (including a bound volume, 1863-87), publications which are printed and in manuscript form, a scrapbook of clippings, miscellaneous reports arranged by date (1878-1920), and photographs. The miscellaneous reports include nurse, intern, and committee reports; visitor of the month reports; and reports of interviews. The bound volume of annual reports also included photographs which were removed and filed separately. Photographs include Ednah Dow Cheney, Susan Dimock, Elizabeth Keller, Mary G. Boardman, Emily Pope, C. Augusta Pope, Samuel E. Sewall, Emma Culbertson and Elizabeth Cushing Abbott, Marie Zakrzewska, Linda Richards, and several miscellaneous pictures. There is also a file of photographs and pictures of eminent people which was originally included with the autograph section of the records. These include William Ellery Channing, Thomas Wentworth Higginson, Ralph Waldo Emerson, Henry Wadsworth Longfellow, and Julia Ward Howe.
- SERIES II. PERSONNEL 1868-1963, 3.75 linear ft.
  This series contains material about the physicians, nurses, and interns of the NEH. It includes minutes of physicians meetings, printed and biographical material, writings, reports, and interns applications files (1891-1926). Of particular interest are copies of 113 photographs from the nursing school class of 1904 which relate to Bessie H. Simpson. The names of the interns, by year, are listed in Appendix I. In addition to the minutes of physicians meetings, of particular interest is a report by Alice Bigelow written in 1951 about her experience at NEH beginning as an intern in 1905. Shel also writes about the experiences of her father, noted Boston physician, Dr. George Bigelow, who also worked at NEH. This report relates in part to African-American interns at the hospital.
  [see also SERIES III. CORRESPONDENCE]
- SERIES III. FINANCIAL 1860-1920, .5 linear ft.
  This series consists of finance committee minutes and reports (1877-1915), correspondence, and bills. The correspondence is arranged by author and it is mostly addressed to George Goddard, who was treasurer of NEH from 1877 to1917. It consists mostly of letters related to the physical plant, donations, audits, and the general operation of the NEH. Included is a letter book of Sarah Crawford, Resident Physician, which contains screening of applicants and patients for charity. It also contains a letter of recommendation for Mary Mahoney as nurse. The bills and invoices are arranged by date.
- SERIES IV. CORRESPONDENCE 1847-1928, .75 linear ft.
  This series consists of general correspondence arranged alphabetically. Correspondents include Ednah Dow Cheney, Mary Putnam Jacobi, C. Augusta and Emily F. Pope, and Marie Zakrzewska. Subject matter consists mostly of resignations, applications, and general hospital business. However, the correspondence of Ednah Dow Cheney (1847-90) contains personal correspondence with Eva and Susan Channing and other friends. There is also a series of condolence letters to and from the Board of Directors.
- SERIES V. SUBJECTS 1876-1963, .25 linear ft.
  The subject series consists of material related to an abortion controversy (1915), the use of chloroform as anesthetic (1888), African-American women interns (1911), nurses examinations (1894), rules and regulations of the hospital (1876-1914), Tufts Medical School affiliation in obstetrics (1913-1914), and the Women's Hospital Training School for Nurses in Philadelphia (1878).
- SERIES VI. AUTOGRAPH COLLECTION 1792-1905, 2 linear ft.
  This series is divided into two subseries: Letters and Autographs. The Letters are arranged by author and are mostly written to Ednah Dow Cheney and Eva Channing, although there is a small group of letters written to Gabriel and William M. Rosetti. Subject List for a list of notable people. Topics include woman suffrage, social services, abolition, freedmen's education, literature, and Civil War relief. This subseries contains letters of Susan Brudick (later Channing) while teaching in New Bedford and Lowell before her marriage (1840-50); and manuscript poems by Henry Wadsworth Longfellow, Bayard Taylor, and Adeline Dutton Whitney. The Autographs consists of autographs on cards, letter fragments, documents, short letters, and postcards as well as a catalog of prices received at the Hospital fairs. A complete list can be found in Appendix II.
- SERIES I. HISTORY 1859-1994
  - Articles, pamphlets, and memoranda, 1877-1994, undated (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Fairs, 1896, 1899 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Fund drive, 1916, [see OVERSIZE MATERIALS] (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Anniversaries
    - 70th-99th, 1931-61 (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - 100th, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Publications
    - Miscellaneous, 1934, 1960-94, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
    - Circulars, 1859, 1860s (Box 1, Folder 7)
    - The Hilltop, yearbook of the graduating class 1946 (Box 1, Folder 8)